Kevin L. Miller, Ph.D.

klmille@gmail.com | (310) 562-4572 | Los Angeles, CA 90230

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/kevin-miller-phd-1b197986/ | GitHub: github.com/Koldenblue

Portfolio: <u>kevin-miller-react-portfolio.herokuapp.com</u>

SUMMARY

Full-Stack Web Developer with a Ph.D. in chemistry from the University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA). Education in full-stack development from UCLA. Experienced problem-solver and scientific researcher with major publications. Values ethics, integrity, and good business sense, having spent years as a business manager and scientist. Extensive teaching experience stems from being both a classroom teacher and a group fitness leader, which lend themselves to public speaking and teamwork skills. Top aim is to contribute to a team while continuously improving coding skills. Seeks to improve the lives of both teammates and clients, whether that be in the real world or the digital world.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- JavaScript/HTML/CSS used as main coding languages
- Emphasis on MERN stack technologies (MongoDB, Express, React, and Node.js)
- React and Express frameworks for front-end and back-end design, routing, and client-server communication
- MongoDB for non-relational database management, along with the Mongoose Object Document Mapper (ODM) or mongo.js package
- Structured Query Language (SQL) database work, through MySQL and the Sequelize Object-Relational Mapper (ORM)
- Coding techniques include object-oriented programming, asynchronous function handling, Application Programming Interface (API) integration, responsive web design, and code testing
- AJAX calls for retrieving data from and interacting with APIs
- ¡Query, Bootstrap, Handlebars, and other established libraries for streamlining web development
- Researching technologies or libraries as needed for example, Moment.js or small packages found with Node Package Manager, such as Inquirer
- Ability to quickly learn additional programming languages and techniques for example, Python and C/C++ programming accomplished through self-study and professional certification

PROJECTS

Inform and React | https://inform-react.herokuapp.com/ | github.com/Koldenblue/Inform-and-React

- React-driven app that provides crucial information to voters, through AJAX calls to various informational API databases and storage of user information with MongoDB
- Executed lead back-end scripting for a team of coders. Programmed all routes and led database design. Performed code review, React component design, and overall project design.

Express Bartender | https://team-express-bartender.herokuapp.com | github.com/FuDoggy/project2

- A collaboratively designed app that provides a searchable SQL database of drinks. Custom user recipes may be stored in the database. Initial database information was acquired using API calls.
- Led the team in database design and storage of user information. Reviewed team code and contributed assistance to front-end website design.

Color Rippler | https://color-rippler.herokuapp.com/ | github.com/Koldenblue/color-rippler

- Generates an interactive grid of colors in a browser. Takes advantage of the React framework to efficiently render a large number of interactive components.
- Combines artistic front-end design with algorithms for dynamic interactivity.

EMPLOYMENT

Twinwood, Inc.:

Property Manager and Accountant

October 2013 - Present

- Rigorous documentation and coordination of large construction projects, with spending ranges in the hundreds of thousands of dollars, directly benefited both tenants and the company
- Meticulous business analytics helped achieve a yearly company growth rate of 3.6% of net worth

Praxair:

Lab Technician and Analytical Scientist

October 2014 - February 2015

• Carefully managed lab testing allowed for a fast throughput of dozens of highly pure gasses daily

University of California, Los Angeles:

Researcher / Teaching Assistant

Sept. 2007 - July 2013

- Intense scientific research led to seven published research papers
- Personal mentoring of two undergraduates helped them publish their own scientific papers
- Chemistry research was awarded Ralph and Charlene Bauer Award, and led to two separate fellowship awards
- Close supervision was performed for hundreds of undergraduate students in both labs and discussion sections, during teaching of over a dozen college-level chemistry discussion courses

EDUCATION

Coding Bootcamp - UCLA Extension

October 2020

CS50 Professional Certificate - HarvardX Online

to be completed October 2020

Ph.D., Chemistry - University of California, Los Angeles

Dec. 2014

B.S., Chemistry - University of California, Irvine

June 2007

LEADERSHIP, COMMUNITY, AND ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Fitness Instructor at Santa Monica Family YMCA

Oct. 2017 - Present

- Consistent teaching of public-facing kickboxing and choreographed dance requires an ingrained positive team mentality
- Enthusiasm for teaching led to a fellowship award for dance
- Certified in CPR / AED, Pediatric CPR, and First Aid by the American Red Cross

Music

 Self-taught bass and guitar skills, a background in music theory, and experience with classical trombone have led to collaborations on a published album and various public shows